<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Feathr Findr</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="enter_your_email">Enter Your Email .....</string>
    <string name="enter_your_pass">Enter Your Password .....</string>
    <string name="re_enter_your_pass">Re-enter Your Password .....</string>
    <string name="sign_up">Sign Up</string>
    <string name="sign_in">Sign In</string>
    <string name="already_registered">Already Registered !!</string>
    <string name="not_registered">Not Registered Yet !!</string>

    <string-array name="sort_types">
        <item>SORT BY DATE</item>
        <item>SORT BY NAME</item>
        <item>SORT BY RARITY</item>
        <item>SORT BY NOTES</item>
        <item>SORT BY DATE</item>
    </string-array>
    <string name="title_activity_mark_bird_location">Mark bird location</string>

    <string name="my_map_api_key">AIzaSyDpx2u8q9f6mqVPiFJXVgb_7aW38rmInyw</string>


    <string name="African_jacanas">Adult African jacanas are medium-sized waterbirds with long necks, long legs, and short tails. Their enormous feet are by far their most unique feature and feature elongated toes that help them walk on floating vegetation. Their length ranges between nine and 12 inches, with the females averaging slightly larger. They weigh around four to 12 ounces and have 20-inch wingspans. These jacanas are predominantly a reddish brown color with a yellow breast. Their head and neck are black on the back and white on the front with short blue bills and black eye strips. </string>
    <string name="Lilac_breasted_roller">The Lilac Breasted Roller is 14.5 inches in length on average. The washed green head is huge, the neck is short, the legs are short, and the feet are little. The beak is powerful, arched, and hooked at the tip. The tail is modest in length and thin. Brown on the back and scapulars. The wing shoulder, outside webs of the flight feathers, and rump are all violet. The primaries and coverts bases are pale greenish blue, while the outer tail feathers are elongated and blackish. The chin is pale, and the breast is a beautiful lilac. The underparts are greenish blue in colour. The eyes are brown and the bill is black. It has broad wings and a powerful flight.</string>
    <string name="Grey_Crowned_Crane">The elegant Grey crowned crane is one of Africa’s most majestic and beautiful birds. It is the national symbol and the national bird of Uganda. The name is due to its yellow crown of feathers, tipped with black. This crane moves gracefully in a most stately manner with a very dignified gait. In flight it is beautiful, using slow down strokes followed by quick upward strokes of its wings.</string>
    <string name="Hoopoe">About 28 centimetres (11 inches) long, it is pinkish brown on the head and shoulders, with a long, black-tipped, erectile crest and black-and-white barred wings and tail. The hoopoe takes insects and other small invertebrates by probing the ground with its long, downcurved bill. </string>
    <string name="Hamerkop">The Hamerkop is an unusual-looking, dark dusky brown, medium-sized bird with long legs. It weighs about 470 g (female) to 530 g (male), stands about 50 cm tall and has a generally heron-like shape. It has a heavy crest and a flattened, boat-shaped, black bill. The profile of the head looks like a hammer, but is often hidden when the neck is drawn back and the crest rests on its back. The Hamerkop is the only member of the family Scopidae.</string>
    <string name="Oxpecker">There are two species of oxpeckers are similar in appearance. They have brownish-gray feathers with lighter underparts. Their legs are short, and they have three sharp claws facing forward and one facing backward. Oxpecker feet are strong and excellent for clinging to surfaces or climbing. They also have stiff tail feathers, similar to those of a woodpeaker which help them to balance. They have red eyes and bright bills. Yellow-billed oxpeckers have yellow bills tipped in red. They do not have a wattle around their eye. Their rump is light in color like their belly. Red-billed oxpeckers have a red bill, a yellow wattle around their eye, and a dark rump.</string>
    <string name="Saddle_billed_stork">A tall, lanky, black-and-white stork with a unique red, yellow, and black bill. The male has dark-brown eyes, and the female has yellow eyes. In flight, the bird’s massive size, and the dark bands in the center of the white wings are diagnostic. Scarce but conspicuous; mostly resident but can be partially nomadic in parts of the range. Found singly or in pairs at rivers and large undisturbed wetlands, foraging for favorites like catfish, but it will also take frogs, birds, and insects.</string>
    <string name="Hornbill">They are noted for the presence, in a few species, of a bony casque, or helmet, surmounting the prominent bill. They are typically large-headed, with thin necks, broad wings, and long tails. The plumage is brown or black, usually with bold white markings. Hornbills range in size from 40 cm (16 inches), in the smaller Tockus species, to 160 cm (63 inches), in the great hornbill (Buceros bicornis).</string>
    <string name="Sunbirds">There is simply an incredible variety of sunbirds, in a number of different colors and patterns. All sunbirds are relatively small, and have a long beak that curves slightly downward. Their beaks almost resemble those of some species of hummingbird. They range in color from yellow to brown, red, orange, blue, green, and more. The smallest species are around four inches long, and the largest around nine inches long.</string>
    <string name="Malachite_kingfisher">Kingfishers are brightly coloured, and many have loud cries and elaborate courtship displays. Malachite kingfishers are classified as "river kingfishers" in the Alcedinidae family. This little kingfisher can often be found along slow-moving rivers and ponds, perched on aquatic plants or reeds. This familys fishing and breeding habits are typical. Malachite kingfishers are found over most of Sub-Saharan Africa, and the population appears to be steady and unthreatened.</string>
    <string name="Cattle_egret">Western Cattle Egrets are the smallest of the white egrets; they are medium sized heron-like birds, about 46 to 56 cm long with a wingspan of about 88 to96 cm.  The average weight of the adult bird is about 360 g, and males and females are about the same size (Scott 1987). They have a thick neck and a long sharp bill, which is black in juveniles and yellow in adults. The non-breeding adults have greyish-yellow legs; during breeding season however, the legs become bright red.</string>
    <string name="Grey_heron">The plumage of the Grey heron is largely ashy-grey above, and greyish-white below with some black on the flanks. Adults have a head and neck white with a broad black supercilium that terminates in the slender, dangling crest, and bluish-black streaks on the front of the neck. The scapular feathers are elongated and the feathers at the base of the neck are also somewhat elongated. Immature birds lack the dark stripe on the head and are generally duller in appearance than adults, with a grey head and neck, and a small, dark grey crest. The pinkish-yellow beak is long, straight, and powerful, and is brighter in color in breeding adults. The iris is yellow and the legs are brown and very long.</string>
    <string name="Cisticolidae">Cisticola, also called Fantail Warbler, any of about 75 species of the genus Cisticola, belonging to the Old World warbler family, Sylviidae. Some classifications group these species into their own family, the Cisticolidae.They occur in grasslands, thorny scrub, and marshes, most numerously in Africa but also across southern Eurasia to Australia. Some are called cloud-scrapers, from the male’s towering courtship-flight. Cisticolas are notoriously difficult to identify; some species may be distinguished only by the configuration of wing feathers. The plumage is chiefly brown, with or without streaking. The tail usually is broad and rather short and may be pale-tipped.</string>
    <string name="Pink_backed_pelican">Pink-backed pelicans have mostly grey plumage with a pinkish back and underparts. The pink color comes from a gland and is spread while preening. Pink-backed pelicans are one of the smallest pelican species. They are approximately 49 – 51 inches in length, with a bill length of 11 – 15 inches and a wingspan of 7 – 9.5 feet. They weigh between 9 – 15.5 pounds, with females being slightly smaller than males. Pink-backed pelicans may live between 15 – 25 years in the wild and up to 54 years under human care.</string>
    <string name="African_wood_owl">The African wood owl is medium sized at about 33 cm in height and weighs approximately 290 g, with the males and females being alike (Chittenden et al. 2016). Although there is individual variation in coloration from chocolate to buffy-rufous, the African Wood Owl generally has a pale rufous facial disc with fine grey barring, white eyebrows, dark-rimmed eyes, a dark rufous upper part and it lacks ear tuffs</string>
    <string name="Barn_owl">Western Barn Owls are medium-sized, measuring 30–33 cm in length, with long wings and a short, squarish tail. Females (weighing around 365 g) are slightly smaller than males, which weigh up to 410 g, but both sexes are similar in plumage colouration. The upper body is golden brown, vermiculated (marked with sinuous or wavy lines) with grey, and spotted black and white. The white, heart-shaped facial disk is contrasted by small, brown to black eyes and a beak that varies from a pale pink to a brownish horn. Underparts are white, with fine brown spots, which make the bird look ghost-like in flight. Legs are greyish-brown and are densely covered with feathers</string>
    <string name="Black_stork">The black stork is a large bird, measuring between 95 and 100 cm (37 and 39 in) in length with a 145-to-155 cm (57-to-61 in) wingspan, and weighing around 3 kg (6.6 lb). Standing as tall as 102 cm (40 in), it has long red legs, a long neck and a long, straight, pointed red beak. It bears some resemblance to Abdims stork which can be distinguished by its much smaller build, predominantly green bill, legs and feet, and white rump and lower back. The plumage is black with a purplish green sheen, except for the white lower breast, belly, armpits, axillaries and undertail coverts. The breast feathers are long and shaggy, forming a ruff which is used in some courtship displays. The black stork has brown irises, and bare red skin around its eyes. The sexes are identical in appearance, except that males are larger than females on average. Moulting takes place in spring, with the iridescent sheen brighter in new plumage. It walks slowly and steadily on the ground and like all storks, it flies with its neck outstretched.</string>
    <string name="Secretarybird"> The Secretarybird is a large-bodied bird of prey with an eagle-like head and crane-like legs. They are 0.9 to 1.2 m tall and weigh between 2.3 and 4.27 kg. Sexual dimorphism is clearly observed in Secretarybirds with males being slightly larger than females. The female wing span ranges between 1.2 and 1.32 m while the male wingspan ranges between 1.26 and 1.35 m.</string>

</resources>